In this video, we're going to being our discussions of run time structures with
在这段视频中，我们将讨论运行时结构
the notion of procedure activations. Before we begin the discussion of
程序激活的概念。在我们开始讨论……之前
activations, it's worth being explicit that we have two overall goals in code
激活，值得明确的是，我们在代码中有两个总体目标
generation. One needs to be correct to generate code that actually faithfully
一代人。生成的代码必须是正确的，这样才能真实地生成
implements the programmer's program And the second is to be efficient that, that
实现程序员的程序，第二是要高效，那就是
code should made good use of resources and in particular we often care that it run
代码应该很好地利用资源，尤其是我们通常关心它是否运行
quickly And is very easy to solve These problems in isolation. If all we care
快速且非常容易孤立地解决这些问题。如果我们都在乎
about is correctness, it's not a hard problem to generate Code that is very
关于正确性，生成非常简单的代码并不是一个困难的问题
simple but also very slow and correctly implements the program. If all we care
简单，但也非常慢，正确地实现了程序。如果我们都在乎
about is speed, we don't care about getting the right answer, the problem is
关于速度，我们不在乎得到正确的答案，问题是
even easier. I can generate extremely fast programs that generate the wrong answer
更简单了。我可以生成速度极快的程序，而这些程序会生成错误的答案
for any problem that you carry to me And so really all the complications in code
对于您带给我的任何问题，以及代码中的所有复杂问题
generation arise from trying to solve These two problems simultaneously And,
产生于试图同时解决这两个问题，
what has grown up over time is fairly elaborate framework for how a code
随着时间的推移，发展起来的是一个相当精细的框架，用于说明代码如何
generator and the run, and the corresponding run time structures should
生成器和运行，以及相应的运行时结构应
be done to achieve both of these goals, okay? And the first step in talking about
去实现这两个目标，好吗？而谈论这一问题的第一步
that is to talk about activations. We're going to make two assumptions about the
那就是说激活。我们要对这个问题做两个假设
kinds of programming languages for which we're generating code. The first
我们正在为其生成代码的各种编程语言。第一个
assumption is that execution is sequential. Given that we execute the
假设执行是按顺序进行的。假设我们执行
statement, the next statement that will be executed is easy to predict. In fact, it's
语句，则很容易预测将执行的下一条语句。事实上，这是
just a function of the statement that we just executed. So, controls is going to
只是我们刚刚执行的语句的函数。因此，控制系统将会
move from one point in a program to another in some well defined order. The
以某种明确定义的顺序从程序中的一个点移动到另一个点。这个
second assumption is the one that procedure is called controllable always
第二个假设是程序总是可控的。
return to the point immediately after the call. That is if I execute a procedure f,
呼叫结束后立即返回该点。也就是说，如果我执行过程f，
once f is done executing, control will always return to the statement that
一旦f执行完毕，控制将始终返回到
followed Point where f was call And there are certainly programming languages and
跟随调用f的Point，肯定有编程语言和
programming lan guage features that violate this assumption. So the most
对违反此假设的语言规范特征进行编程。所以最多的
important class of programming language is it violate assumption one are ones that
重要的一类编程语言是否违反了假设一
have concurrency. So the concurring program just because I execute one
具有并发性。所以并发程序仅仅因为我执行了一个
statement there is no easy way to predict what the next statement is to execute it
语句中，没有简单的方法来预测要执行它的下一条语句是什么。
because it might be in a completely different thread. And for assumption too
因为它可能在一个完全不同的线程中。对于假设也是如此
Advanced control constructs things like exceptions And Calls [cough]. If you
高级控制构造异常和调用(咳嗽)之类的东西。如果你
happen to know what call cc is, it's not important if you don't. These kinds of
碰巧知道什么叫抄送，如果你不知道也不重要。这些类型的
constructs that affect the flow of control in fairly dramatic ways can violate
以相当戏剧性的方式影响控制流的构造可能会违反
assumption to. So in particular, if you're familiar with catch and throw style
假设。尤其是，如果你熟悉接球和投掷的风格
exceptions in Java and C++, when we throw an exception that exception might escape
Java和C++中的异常，当我们抛出异常时，该异常可能会转义
from multiple procedures before it is caught and so there's no guarantee when
在它被捕获之前来自多个程序，所以不能保证什么时候
you call a procedure if that procedure can throw an exception that, that it control
如果过程可以抛出它控制的异常，则调用该过程
whatever return to the point immediately after the procedure call. Now, we're gonna
在过程调用之后立即返回到该点的任何内容。现在，我们要
keep these assumptions for the rest of the class. We may later on in future videos
把这些假设留给班上的睡觉吧。我们稍后可能会在未来的视频中
briefly discuss how we would accommodate some of these more advanced features if
简要讨论我们将如何适应这些更高级的功能，如果
the, the material that we're going to cover. Is basic to all implementation and
我们要讲的材料。是所有实施的基础，并且
even languages have concurrency and exception build upon the ideas that we're
即使是语言也有并发和异常，它们都是建立在这样的思想之上的，那就是我们正在
going to discuss here. So first the definition When we invoke the procedure p.
我要在这里讨论一下。首先是我们调用过程p时的定义。
We're going to say that is an activation of the procedure p and the life time of an
我们会说这是程序p的激活和一个
activation of p is gonna be all the steps are involved executing the procedure p and
激活p将是所有步骤都涉及到执行过程p和
including all the steps in the procedures that p calls so it's going to be all the
包括p调用的过程中的所有步骤，所以这将是所有
steps in the procedures that p calls. So it's going to be all the statements that
p调用的过程中的步骤。所以这将会是所有的陈述
are executed between the moment that p is called and the moment that p returns
在调用p的时刻到p返回的时刻之间执行
including all the functions and procedures that p itself calls. We could define an
包括p本身调用的所有函数和过程。我们可以定义一个
analogous notion of the lifetime of a variable. So the lifetime of a variable x
变量寿命的类似概念。所以变量x的寿命
is gonna be the portion of the execution in which x is defined, That means that
将是执行中定义x的部分，这意味着
it's all the step of execution from the time that x is first created until the
这是从x第一次创建到
time when x is destroyed or deal located and just note here that life time is a
x被破坏或被定位的时间，这里只需注意生命时间是
dynamic concept so this is that implies to the executing program. We're talking about
动态概念，所以这对正在执行的程序来说是隐含的。我们在谈论的是
the time when the variable first comes into existence until the moment in time
变量第一次出现的时间，直到该时刻为止
when it goes out of existence And scope on the other hand is a static concept that go
另一方面，当它走出存在和范围的时候，是一个静电的概念
prefers to that portion of the program text in which the variable is visible.
首选程序文本中变量可见的部分。
Okay, so this is a very different idea from the life time of the variable and
好的，这是一个非常不同的概念，与变量的生存期不同，
again. It's very important to keep these two times, what happens at runtime and
再来一次。保持这两个时间是非常重要的，在运行时和
what happens in compiler time or what is associated with the static properties of
编译时会发生什么，或者与的静电属性关联的是什么
the program distinct in your mind. From the assumptions that we gave a couple of
这个节目在你脑海中清晰可见。根据我们给出的几个假设
slides ago we can make a simple observation and that is when a procedure P
幻灯片之前，我们可以做一个简单的观察，那就是当一个程序P
calls the procedure Q. Then Q is going to return before P returns. And what that
调用过程Q，然后Q将在P返回之前返回。那又是什么呢？
means is that the lifetime of procedures are going to be properly nested and
意味着过程的生存期将被适当地嵌套，并且
furthermore, that means that we can illustrate or represent activation
此外，这意味着我们可以说明或表示激活
lifetimes as a tree. Let's illustrate activation with a simple example. So
一生如一棵树。让我们用一个简单的例子来说明激活。所以
here's a little cool program and as usual, it will begin running by executing the
下面是一个很酷的小程序，像往常一样，它将通过执行
main method in the main class. So the first activation and the root for our
Main类中的Main方法。所以我们的第一个激活和根
activation tree for this program is the method main. And. Main is going to call
此程序的激活树是Main方法。和。Main要打电话给你
the method g and so g's lifetime, the set of instructions were g exist where a
方法g和g的生命周期，指令集是g，其中a
period of time of the execution where g existed is gonna be properly contain
在g存在的地方执行的时间段将被适当地包含
within the execution of this call to main. And so we can illustrate that by making g
在此Main调用的执行过程中。所以我们可以通过制作g来说明这一点。
a child of main. So this indicates that effect of g is a direct child of main
美因河畔的一个孩子。因此，这表明g的效果是main的直接子效果。
indicates that main calls g and also the g's lifetime is properly contained within
指示main调用g以及g的生存期正确包含在
the lifetime of main. After g returns main will call f and so f will also. The, a
Main的生命周期。在g返回后，main将调用f，因此f也将调用。这个，一个
child of, of main And then F as itself is going to call G again And so, it's gonna
Main的子级，然后F本身将再次调用G，所以它将
have another activation of G And so G Will also be a child of f. And this tree that
有G的另一个激活，因此G也将是f的子树。这棵树
is actually the complete tree for this particular example illustrates the number
实际上是此特定示例的完整树，说明了数字
of things. First of all as we already said it shows the containment of life time. So
所有的东西。首先，正如我们已经说过的，它显示了生命时间的限制。所以
again for example g's life time is contained with a name but it also shows
同样，例如，g的寿命包含一个名称，但它还显示
some other interesting lifetime relationships. For example, the life time
其他一些有趣的终生恋情。例如，生命周期
of this activation of g and the life time of that activation of f are completely
g的激活和f的激活的寿命完全是
distinct because their siblings in the tree, their lifetimes do no overlap at
因为它们在树上的兄弟姐妹是不同的，所以它们的生命周期在
all. And another thing to notice here is that there can be multiple occurrences of
全。这里需要注意的另一件事是，可以多次出现
the same method in the activation tree. So every time the method is called that is a
激活树中的相同方法。因此，每次调用该方法时，都是一个
separate activation so in this particular activation tree there are two activations
分开激活，因此在此特定激活树中有两个激活
of g. So, here's a somewhat more complicated example the involves a
所以，这里有一个稍微复杂的例子，它涉及一个
recursive function. Let's begin here at the, at the first call. So The call to
递归函数。让我们从这里开始，从第一个电话开始。因此，对
main And all main does is call F with the argument three. So, there is an activation
Main和所有Main所做的都是使用参数3调用F。所以，有一种激活
of F from Main. And then what does f do, well f asks if it's argument is zero, and
来自Main的F。然后f做什么呢，好吧，f问它的参数是否为0，
if it is that calls g, while the initial argument is three so that's not going to
如果是，则调用g，而初始参数是3，所以不会
be true on the first call to f. In otherwise, it calls f with the argument
在第一次调用f时为true。否则，它将使用以下参数调用f
minus one. So, I was making note over here on the side about what the argument is
减一。所以，我在边上记下了争论是什么
because we need to keep track of that. So f is called with three clearly that is not
因为我们需要跟踪这一点。所以调用f时有三个显然不是
zero, and so then f is going to be called again with the argument two, that will
0，然后用参数2再次调用f，这将是
results in f being called yet another time with the argument one and finally, f will
导致使用参数1再次调用f，最后，f将
be called. With the argument zero, Which will then result in a call to G, And so
被召唤。参数为0，这将导致对G的调用，因此
this is the activation tree for this particular program, And again notice that
这是此特定程序的激活树，请再次注意
there is gonna be multiple activation of the procedure on the same run of the
在同一运行中将有多个过程激活
program. It just indicates that the same procedure can be called multiple times and
程序。它只是表明同一过程可以被多次调用，并且
also note that the recursive procedure will result in nesting of activations of
还要注意，递归过程将导致嵌套激活
the same function within itself, And so when f calls i tself and so the life time
在其内部有相同的函数，所以当f调用i时，也就是生命周期
say of the second call to f is properly contained within the life time with the
假设对f的第二次调用正确地包含在生存期内，
fist call to f.
第一次呼叫f。